<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Left Tapes</title><link>http://www.lefttapes.org.uk/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://www.lefttapes.org.uk/feeds/all.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 09:45:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Digitising 4-track cassettes - part 2</title><link>http://www.lefttapes.org.uk/digitising-4-track-cassettes-part-2.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As is often the case, it was &lt;a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk"&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt; that came to the rescue. Portastudios appear sporadically and sell for a not-unreasonable price. I got lucky almost straight away with a &lt;a href="https://www.soundonsound.com/sos/mar01/articles/tascamporta.htm"&gt;424 Mk &lt;span class="caps"&gt;III&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of the last of the range, restyled for the late 90s with a pale blue finish, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LED&lt;/span&gt; displays and a digital transport. I sniped it for £85, which seemed like a bargain after their unthinkable prices to the teenage me. However, for all its modern looks, it had also departed from previous designs by taking the power supply out of the main box and providing a separate transformer with a semi-proprietary power socket which seemed to be rarer than sparks of humanity in the Department of Work and Pensions, and which didn&amp;#8217;t arrive in the box that came with the Portastudio in it. The seller couldn&amp;#8217;t find it either, and eBay didn&amp;#8217;t come through in this case, so this lovely piece of obsolete technology went back to its&amp;nbsp;seller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately it didn&amp;#8217;t take long for another one to appear, and in the kind of serendipity that only happens to other people, it was a &lt;a href="http://en.audiofanzine.com/analog-multitrack-studio/tascam/Portastudio-464/user_reviews/"&gt;464&lt;/a&gt; in Huddersfield, for collection only. This was a win on several levels: the 464 is a rare machine with six channels on the mixer instead of the usual four and most people look for the more standard 424. Plus it was in Huddersfield. I won it for £35 and the next weekend went to collect it from the suburbs of the town. It was great to be able to play these old tapes again at last. The next thing was to work out how to transcribe&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simon Greenwood</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 09:45:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:www.lefttapes.org.uk,2015-08-01:digitising-4-track-cassettes-part-2.html</guid><category>vanity</category><category>archiving</category><category>recording</category></item><item><title>Digitising 4-track cassettes - part 1</title><link>http://www.lefttapes.org.uk/digitising-4-track-cassettes-part-1.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It hadn&amp;#8217;t occurred to me to do anything with the pile of tapes I&amp;#8217;ve been amassing and carrying around for getting on for thirty years, but when I sold my house in 2014 and stopped using it as a spare room while living in the house I now shared with my wife and daughter, they had to go somewhere. There was a pile of pre-recorded tapes that I had collected from the 80s and into the 90s before that technology died off, a smaller pile of independent tapes in duplicated sleeves and a collection of not-quite highest quality blank cassettes that contained the results of a year or so of intensive recording in the early&amp;nbsp;1990s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was how to get the music off them. Almost 25 years after the fact, Portastudios are rare things, museum pieces at best. To make things more complicated, the original device was the budget &lt;a href="http://www.elvenminstrel.com/recording/portas/model-portaone.htm"&gt;Porta One&lt;/a&gt;, which recorded at 1 7/8 inches per second, standard cassette speed, where the majority of Portastudios did 3 3/4 ips, double speed. So the search was on to find something to play the cassettes&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Simon Greenwood</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 23:50:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:www.lefttapes.org.uk,2015-07-31:digitising-4-track-cassettes-part-1.html</guid><category>vanity</category><category>archiving</category><category>recording</category></item></channel></rss>